彼得：每当我在一个普通观众面前谈论机器人，某人时
Peter: Whenever I give a talk somewhere to a general audience about robots, somebody
总是问我关于工作的问题;机器人不会把我们的工作带走吗？和论点
always asks me the question about jobs; won’t robots take our jobs away? And the argument
我经常做的是'是的，他们会带走一些工作，这是不舒服的，
I usually make is 'yeah, they're going to take some jobs away and that's uncomfortable,
但另一种选择是，如果我们没有在工厂工作的机器人，我们可能就是这样
but the alternative is if we don't have robots working in factories, the likelihood is we
将完全失去这个行业。
will lose the industry entirely.'
所以我们做了一些交易。我们将继续保持行业，例如，我们
So we're making a bit of a trade. We're going to keep the industry, for instance, we're
将汽车制造业保持在劳动力成本高的国家，并且这样做
going to keep manufacturing automobiles in a high labor cost country and it's going to
雇用一些人，它将采用一些税收，这将是一个巨大的打击
employ some people and it's going to employ some taxes and there's going to be a big knock
关于经济利益，但是，是的，绝对会对就业产生一些影响。
on economic benefit, but yeah, absolutely, it will have some impact on jobs.
最近，关于所谓的新机器时代已有相当多的文章
More recently, there's been quite a bit written about the so-called new machine age where
整个工作岗位，不一定是手工劳动工作，很多所谓的知识工作者
a whole raft the jobs, not necessarily manual labor jobs, a lot of so-called knowledge worker
工作也许会消失，比如解释X光片并撰写财务报告。现在
jobs will perhaps disappear, like interpreting X-rays and writing financial reports. Now
这些都是现在的工作。
these are jobs now that are on the line.
曾经有一位非常着名的哲学家伏尔泰谈到了工作的美德
There's a once upon a time very famous philosopher, Voltaire, talked about the virtues of work
我们中的许多人定义自己或我们的身份，我们的自尊，这一切都包含在内
and many of us define ourselves or our identity, our self-esteem, it’s all wrapped up in
工作。因此，在我看来，这或许是我们今天所讨论的所有主题中最复杂的问题。
work. So this seems to me perhaps the most exquisitely complex of all the topics that we've talked about today.
道德对此有何看法？
What does ethics say about this?
道格：我们的身份被锁定在我们大多数人经常做的事情上。而我们的根本
Doug: Our identity is locked up in what we do often for most of us. And our fundamental
引导我们大多数人的道德哲学来自约翰洛克的劳动理论。约翰
moral philosophy that guides most of us comes out of John Locke's theory of labor. John
洛克的劳动理论是财产权的基础。而这本身就是这样
Locke's theory of labor is the foundation to the rights to property. And that in itself
建立美国宪法的产权基础。
set up the property rights basis of the American Constitution.
因此，财产权以及我们如何定义自己以及如何定义我们的文化
So the rights to property and how we define ourselves and how we define our culture is
锁定了我们的工作。它在自由民主，劳动理论方面根深蒂固，
locked up in what we do. And it's entrenched in terms of liberal democracy, the labor theory,
和功利主义;所有这三种哲学观点都指导着我们如何设定价值观。
and utilitarianism; all three of those philosophical perspectives guide us in terms of how we set our values.
现在，对于取代人类的机器，你将对Luddite革命非常熟悉。
Now with respect to machines replacing humans, you'll be very familiar with the Luddite revolution.
彼得：当然。
Peter: Absolutely.
道格：在早期的工业革命中。
Doug: During the early industrial revolution.
彼得：有大锤子的家伙。
Peter: The guys with big hammers.
道格：是的。他们进去了，他们粉碎了所有的棉纺厂。我想这大约是1790年。
Doug: Yep. They went in and they smashed all the cotton mills. I think it's about 1790.
他们去了那里，因为他们害怕而去了棉纺厂的小镇
They went in there and just went to town on the cotton mills because they're afraid, and
他们在这方面非常正确，棉纺厂将取代他们的工作。他们做到了。
they were quite right in this, that the cotton mills are going to replace their jobs. And they did.
当然，Luddites都很快就被吊死了。维多利亚时代的不当行为规则
Of course, the Luddites were all duly hanged very quickly. Victorian rules for misconduct
这是世界上历史上最严重的一些，但感谢天堂，我们没有
were some of the most severe in the history in the world but thank heavens we don't have
这么多艰难的法律了。
so many hard laws anymore.
但是Luddites有一个合理的立场。然而，自从机器以来，这一直伴随着我们
But the Luddites had a justified position. However, that's been with us since machines
和我们在一起，那种恐惧。天生担心我们不仅会失去工作，
been with us, that fear. That innate fear that we're going to lose not only our jobs,
但我们的身份和我们是谁。
but our identity and who we are.
彼得：自从工业化以来，创造了许多就业机会，然后就消失了。
Peter: And since industrialisation here, so many jobs have been created and then disappeared.
道格：正确。它似乎潮起潮落。我们的劳动力越来越多
Doug: Correct. It seems to ebb and flow. We're getting more and more people in the labor
市场。澳大利亚在过去50年中人口增加了一倍。我们有更多的人在工作。
market. Australia in the last 50 years has doubled in population. We have more people working.
所以我可能对此有点无知，但从我所看到的是我们适应。它的
So I might be a little ignorant on this, but from what I can see is that we adapt. It's
关于人类最有趣的事情之一，就是我们适应和适应的能力
one of the most interesting things about the human being, is our ability to adapt and to
更改。而我们似乎正在这样做。
change. And we seem to be doing that.
因此，这种对机器失去工作的天生恐惧似乎是没有根据的。然而，
And so, this innate fear of losing our jobs to machines seems to be unfounded. However,
我明白了。在道德方面，实际上，这不是一个道德立场
I understand it. In terms of ethics, really, it's not an ethical position that you can
采取。我猜个人需要有自主权来选择并能够工作
take. I guess individuals need to have the autonomy to choose and to be able to work
并且能够生活在自由的环境中并且能够访问这些资源
and to be able to live in a free environment and to have access to those resources, so
这在道德上非常重要。
that's very important ethically.
但是机器将把它带走的论点，我已经看到了一些证据
But the argument that machines are going to take that away, I've seen some evidence of
它最近关闭了南澳大利亚的Holden工厂，但最底层
it recently with the closure of the Holden facilities in South Australia, but bottom
现在我们正在谈论潜艇，我想，昨天的新闻？
line is - now we're talking about submarines, I think, yesterday on the news?
彼得：是的。
Peter: Yep.
道格：并且可能将更多的工作整合到澳大利亚并将其发送出去
Doug: And integrating maybe more work back into Australia and send it off, putting it
进入日本重新设计和重建在澳大利亚的潜艇。因此，它起伏不定。
into Japan for re-designing and rebuilding submarines back in Australia. So, it ebbs and flows.
彼得：那么就个人而言，如果他们没有工作，那就是道德考虑
Peter: So in the case of an individual, if they don't have a job, the ethical consideration
这是我们是否会影响他们的自治。
here is whether we impinge on their autonomy.
道格：是的，没错。在这种文化中有基本的权利可以拥有充实的生活。
Doug: Yes, correct. And there are basic right to have a fulfilled life in this culture.
彼得：但在我们的文化中，一个充实的生活通常包括一份工作。
Peter: But in our culture a fulfilled life usually includes a job.
道格：嗯，它包括工作权和获得工作和资源的权利。
Doug: Well, it includes the right to work and the right to have access to work and resources.
是的，它确实。
Yes, it does.
彼得：所以我们可以在人们头上盖一个屋顶，我们可以确保他们不饿
Peter: So we could put a roof over people's heads, we can make sure that they're not hungry
所以他们会在某种意义上照顾，舒服，但他们可能没有工作选择。
and so they would be in some sense looked after, comfortable, but they may not have the option of a job.
道格：是的。我认为更大的问题是，机器是否会夺走工作机会？换句话说，如果我们看一下......
Doug: Yeah. I think the bigger question is, are machines taking away jobs? In other words, if we look at…
彼得：总的来说。
Peter: In an overall sense.
彼得：是的，他们会带走一些，但其他工作将会到来。
Peter: Yes, they're going to take away some but then other jobs are going to come.
道格：其他工作将用机器创造，所以似乎有一个平衡点
Doug: And other jobs will be created with the machines, so there seems to be a balance
那里。和往常一样，这是一种平衡，我认为这是一种凝聚力
there. And as always, there's a balance, and I think that there's a cohesion in terms of
创造就业机会和失去似乎正在努力的工作。我没有
the creation of jobs and the loss of jobs that seems to be working on. I don't have
关于那个的统计数据但这将是一个有趣的...
stats on that but that would be an interesting…
彼得：我的意思是，它已经消失了一百年或更长时间。
Peter: I mean, it's the way it's gone for hundred years or more.
道格：当然，是的。
Doug: Absolutely, yeah.
彼得：问题在于我们是否会突然出现某种临界点
Peter: The issue is whether we're going to some kind of tipping point where suddenly
不再持有，并且有一些书说这种情况，但我不认为
that no longer holds, and there is some books that say that that's case, but I don't think
我们-我不确定是否有人可以做出混合硬性或坚定的预测。
we- I'm not sure anyone can make a hybrid hard or firm prediction about that.
道格：是的，所以我没有答案，因为如果是这样的话，让我们的项目......
Doug: Yeah, so I don't have an answer to that because if it's the case, let's project…
彼得：好的。
Peter: Okay.
道格：如果是这样，比如100年，机器真的几乎取代了你和我。
Doug: If it's the case, say, in 100 years, that machines have really pretty much replaced you and me.
彼得：是的。
Peter: Yup.
道格：我们不再需要教授，我们在那里有一个忘记了更多的机器人
Doug: We don't need professors anymore, we've got an android there that forgot more about
比道格贝克所知道的道德规范，我们在这里有另一个道德，好吧，
ethics than Doug Baker will ever know, and we've got another one over here that, well,
他将彼得·科克的大脑编入他的脑中，而他还有另外三个大脑
he's got Peter Corke's brain programmed into him and he's got about three more other brains
编入他的程序，他可以教所有关于机器人的东西。
programmed into him and he can teach everything there is about robotics.
那么接下来的问题是，你和我这样的人呢？我们可能会这样做
So the question then is this, what are guys like you and me do? We'll probably be doing
但是我不确定是什么。那么问题就在于我们是否接管了这些工作
something but I'm not sure what. And the question then is if we have the jobs taken over by
机器，人类做什么？我们是否为此获得了价值，或者我们可能在年龄退休
machines, what do humans do? Do we get value for that or maybe we retire at the age of
30，或许我们不工作？我不知道。
30, or maybe we don't work? I don't know.
彼得：我认为另一件事是我们长大了。我们谈到了那个人
Peter: Which is the other thing that I think is we grow up. We talked about that the people
将会提前退休以及所有这些，而且这种情况也没有发生。
would be retiring earlier and all this, and that didn't happen either.
道格：不。
Doug: No.
彼得：退休年龄正在上升。
Peter: The retirement age is going up.
道格：是的，绝对的。是的，绝对是，它正在上升。我不知道那是什么。
Doug: Yeah, absolutely. Yeah, absolutely, it is going up. I don't know what that's about.
彼得：不，但我认为这是一个坏主意。
Peter: No, but I think it's a bad idea.
道格：那是真的。但我认为，就道德而言，我认为就是拿走工作
Doug: That's true. But I think that, in terms of ethics, the taking away of jobs, I think
我们需要了解更大的图景以及所创造和所采取的措施的平衡
we need to look at the bigger picture and the balance of what's created and what's taken
离开之前，我们可以做出这个论点。但它确实不是道德的论据。它
away before we can make that argument. But it really isn't an argument for ethics. It
可以作为自治的论据，但总的来说，我不认为这是一个道德问题。一点也不。
can be an argument for autonomy but overall, I don't see that's an ethical issue. Not at all.